Sadjad Tavakoli

🔰 (778)751-6969 🗷 sadjadtavakoli@gmail.com 🛅 sadjadtavakoli 🜎 sadjadtavakoli

About Me

Software engineer with five years of industrial experience, interested in web applications design and development. Observant, punctilious, and innovative; likes redesigning, refactoring, and making codes cleaner. Currently studying Master of Computing Science at Simon Fraser University.

Professional Experience

Intelligent Information Solutions Center (IIS)

Tehran, Iran

Software Engineer

Nov. 2018 - Sep. 2020

Project: Dorna, an executive tracking and monitoring system developed for a company with 1K+ employees and 1M+ terminals.

- Migrated Map service from Google Maps to a local one.
- Pushed forward the project architecture refactoring process from Microservice to Monolithic.
- Delivered External APIs using Django Rest Framework (DRF).

Project: Motoshub, a social network development engine, based on Oxwall, which is currently used by 12 organizations.

- Refactored Chat Service and User-Server interaction to use Websocket instead of API calls.
- Developed and maintained features on both frontend and backend using PHP, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS.

Shopgram Tehran, Iran

A social commerce platform with 200+ sellers and 2k+ active users. This project was later rebranded as SnappShop \mathbb{Z} , which currently has 100K+ active users and 20K+ daily visits.

Software Engineer Apr. 2019 - Sep. 2019

- Refactored and developed chat service implemented by Django Channels.
- Refactored and Wrote unit and integration tests, focused on the integral parts, which increased test coverage from 15% to 60%.
- Refactored two main models and their related views regarding Code Smells and Anti-Patterns.

Lyan Tehran, Iran

A social commerce startup accelerated by SUT . This project was initiated by who Co-Founded three successful projects (TomanPay, Behtarino, and SnappShop). Lyan was later pivoted as Shopgram.

App Team Manager and Product Owner

Apr. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Managed a team of 5 to design and develop two mobile applications for Android and iOS with 100+ APIs.
- Managed the **product ownership** including backlog, roadmap, product release planning using Taiga, based on **Scrum** and **Kanban** principles.
- Collaborated with the marketing team to identify their needs and define product deliverables and release milestones.

Software Engineer

Nov. 2015 - Dec. 2017

- Involved in the full project lifecycle to design, develop, and deploy 300+ APIs and 80+ database models, using Django, DRF, and PostgreSQL.
- Wrote and maintained unit and integration tests with $\sim \%95$ coverage.
- Mentored and managed 10+ interns assigned by the Sharif University of Technology as a part of their education and less experienced software engineers.
- Reviewed 200+ merge requests and coding tasks.
- Technical team representative to the marketing team.

Technical Skills

Languages (sorted by experience and preference): Python, JavaScript, Java, SQL, HTML/CSS, C++, PHP Knowledge: Agile Methodologies, OOP, Design Patterns, Data Structure and Algorithms, Code Smells Tools/Frameworks: Django Rest Framework, Nodejs, Git, Docker, Jenkins, Project Management Tools (Trello, Github, Gitlab, and Taiga)

Education

Simon Fraser University (SFU)

Sep. 2020 - Current (Sep. 2022)

Master of Computing Science Under the Supervision of Dr. Saba Alimadadi, GPA 3.5/4

BC, Canada

- Research Areas: Software Engineering, Software Analysis, Software Comprehension with a focus on Change Impact Analysis
- TA Experiences: Intro to Software Engineering (CMPT 276); Web-based Information Systems (CMPT 470)

Sharif University of Technology (SUT)

Sep. 2013 - Sep. 2019

Bachelor of Software Engineering Under the Supervision of Dr. MohammadAmin Fazli

Tehran, Iran

- Thesis: Computing the Cultural Distance between Countries by Mining Twitter Data (Published in IEEE)
- TA Experiences: Fundamentals of Programming (C Language)

Publications

Issa Annamoradnejad, MohammadAmin Fazli, Jafar Habibi, and Sadjad Tavakoli. Cross-cultural studies using social networks data. *IEEE Transactions on Computational Social Systems*, 6(4):627–636, 2019